[Music]
thank you
hello and welcome to hollow talk the
internet radio broadcast for lasers and
holography enjoyed by listeners
throughout the world I'm Frank defreitis
and I'll be your host for each
installment bringing you news guests and
everything holographic now please enjoy
the latest show
[Music]
thank you
hi Paul how are you it's Frank de
Freitas
how are you how are you doing driving
back to Connecticut out here I am indeed
I thought I'd give you a call and see
what we could do about putting the show
up and having you on the show
I have one of the shows up already with
Michael and
can always put this one up in addition
to that and then send out another email
blast to the subscribers
sounds good so everything's set up and
ready to go I take it I went in uh just
to sort of lay the show out
today
but primarily this is uh our nature of
holography show which is uh it's our
nature of poliner P2 we have two shows
we circulate essentially the same
one Show is bigger than the other
the show in
in reading is
I guess image wise probably a little
over uh 45 50 images wow and uh they're
packed pretty tightly in that show but
it's a it's a nice little show it's uh
sort of an introductory to holography
using images from nature
and it goes through and and talks about
their panels or historical uh timeline
which is sort of uh drawn from our
website on the history of holography
and um and then the images are there to
sort of show people how holography is
different than other uh media like
photography of course
paintings are means there's a nice
little section called the natural
collection which which had 12 embossed
Holograms using a variety of different
embossed
and
you see them of course on the National
Geographic or or your MasterCard and
Visa cards yeah yeah and uh each one of
those images are from nature and they
show how the
show the exact same object done as a
hologram and then as a photograph or as
a pen and ink drawing or as an embossed
well that's that's a nice touch yeah so
there are 12 of them and they're 12
different images and each showing a
holography uh uh versus another type
of representation
which is nice it might be a particularly
interesting to uh graphic art students
who who are dealing with such matters so
that's essentially the show
it's got one of the all-time favorites
of course uh uh uh kiss two by Lloyd
cross yeah which which I I just had to
add in there so it's the only integral
or holographic movie that we have in
there okay but it's such a classic
everything else is is uh reflection
pieces and involves pieces pieces of
course are the transmission mirror back
I imagine it must be a number of pieces
from
Richmond holographics
there are because they produce a ton
of Greg Cherry is in there and
yeah Richmond holographics is definitely
in there because they have some great
images yeah you don't happen to have
lindau man in there do you
we have it in the other show oh okay
and I I was looking around to see if I
could I could find another copy I didn't
want to break up the show because the
other show goes down to
to a museum of
in Daytona Beach okay that's another
question I wanted to ask you because
there are a number of listeners in
Florida that I told there would be a
show down in Florida and they were just
curious why don't you while I have you
on the phone I don't want to hold you up
because I know you have a long drive why
don't you tell the listeners a little
bit about the Florida show too
let's edit this out because I don't have
one I don't have my notes in front of it
all right any dates or anything months
ballpark for those I'm looking for those
right now that's all right
the uh Richmond just just out of
curiosity for the holographers who are
listening
holographic pieces are they on glass
plate or film are they the film they're
all in film okay yep we found that to be
there uh the the best thing to use
because
they're traveling to stuff around
classes is break down pretty easily yeah
yeah
I'm going to do a presentation during
the month and what I'm going to do is I
don't know if anyone spoke to you about
it but I'll be taking a few photographs
of a few selected Holograms
and then telling the stories behind the
Holograms
oh that's nice as part of the
presentation yeah I mean there's an
extra
handwritten written or a series of pages
by Lloyd cross
which you might want to take a look at I
found it fascinating him talking about
the early days of of
uh of the school of Samson School of
hologram yeah
you know but the kiss would be a
fascinating uh uh talk about that as
well because that it just goes there you
know it's a classic the classic image
it's just a great image everybody loved
it well it's Super Bowl weekend that it
opens on so if if anybody's a
holographer and they like the Super Bowl
what a weekend that would be you can go
to the holography exhibit on Saturday
and watch the Super Bowl on Sunday
that's right and of course they're open
for I think this show goes through uh
April April 29th yeah right so there's
there's uh plenty of time to see it and
there's plenty of other things to see at
that museum too I didn't realize that's
a great museum down oh isn't it that's a
beautiful Museum they actually had a
holography exhibit there 20 years ago I
know I know forgotten who who
yeah and I the name that
um well Doug no Doug Tyler no he didn't
no he wasn't doing it then
actually I believe from St Mary's
College or something like that I think
it was is that that's Doug Tyler right
that's right I actually wrote the review
for that show at the reading Museum I'm
not sure if anybody who's at the reading
Museum was there 20 years ago I don't
think anybody remembers it yeah I wrote
the review for that and I actually had
it out a while ago and it was Doug Tyler
who curated the show and St Mary's may
be the wrong name of the college or
whatever but uh
it's tough remembering this stuff for 20
years or more anymore
tell me about it you know uh we were at
you always tell me every time we talk
that you were
a collection of holograms that you saw
was at the uh uh at the Walnut Street
Theater yes when I I was circulating the
Museum of holography uh through the
Looking Glass which is yes absolutely
we opened in at the Walnut Street
Theater oh really and that was our first
show that we went to um uh to Montreal
and then we went down to Charlotte North
or to Raleigh North Carolina where
that's where it started breaking
attendance records you know they had a
one-day attendance record-breaking
broken down there for that show and the
show didn't go uh was out for 10 years
never came back to New York isn't that
something
I had one of the original posters from
that show was actually it wasn't called
through the Looking Glass on the poster
that they sold it was actually called
the Hologram show
oh really yes
admission was 50 cents
for children I believe and a dollar for
adults
mid 70s
yeah
but then then we took a Looking Glass
down to uh to Adelaide Australia
and then uh and then and then eventually
uh it it went over to the Israel Museum
in Jerusalem
so if you've got around for for it was a
nice show and it's sort of debates it's
the same model that the nature of
philography is there are people who have
never really seen a large collection of
holograms yeah you know what it looks
like what it's all about and where it
came from and and maybe a hint of where
it's going well I owe you a great deal
of gratitude for um
for that show because that's what's
actually spurred me on I mean I saw my
first hologram in 68 and was something I
always wanted to do but right after I
saw that show in Philadelphia that's
what cemented it
and then once I bought the house the
holography handbook in 1983 got me
started with my own studio so there
wasn't there wasn't much written on the
holography back now
it was like gold I sat outside of that
Walnut Street Theater in a parking lot
waiting for it to open and in 1962
wildcat
that we we didn't have any heat in the
car and it was in the middle of winter
and we had to wrap ourselves in blankets
because I think we had an hour and a
half before it opened a lot has changed
since then
for sure so uh looks like you're doing a
lot of new stuff there at your studio I
try to keep ahead of the curve you know
you find out anything about the Florida
show
that's all right I have I tell you what
I I I'm I'm running around with limited
limited files don't worry about it we'll
uh we'll get that information out to the
listeners one school in particular in
Jacksonville was interested in we have
holography as part of their program
there is that right yeah you know I
noticed you know on my site I get uh you
know side meters here and see where
people come from and it's just amazing
the number of uh
in colleges that that
that
um
send people to the history of holography
I guess just to sort of get them up to
speed on where where it came from that's
on our website that history page that
you had to have is wonderful I actually
link over to that too it's a wonderful
history page
and I can I keep adding stuff every once
in a while
unfortunately most recently since Leath
and
passed on and of course our Guru Steve
Benton yeah yeah
all right anything else you want to add
to to let people know about from the
actual curator of the show
well I think that's about it
back to you on
I know you have a long trip back but you
were so close to my house
right where are you right now well I you
know
[Music]
well you're more than welcome to come by
if you'd like to I might try that on the
way down I'm going to come down and
break the show and then take
it all right let's plan on that we'll
have a lunch or dinner all right that
sounds good okay either go out for
dinner or I can cook either either way
you can cook yeah I can cook
well I'm Amazed
it comes from mixing all the chemicals
yeah you just substitute the herbs and
spices in your cup
all right Paul I'll let you get back on
the road all right hey
hopefully everything goes as plans for a
big opening weekend all right well
thanks again for your support and help
there Frank oh thank you and look
forward to seeing the show and look
forward to seeing people during my
presentation days take care Paul thank
you for calling